Kishan Narotam

Senior Associate Consultant +27 72 619 1929 knarotam@gmail.com knarotam.github.io Johannesburg, South Africa KEY SKILLS Time & Self Management Communication Leadership Complex Problem Solving Analytical Skills (Business and Data)

EDUCATION

Software Development

MBA in Business Analytics

Universidad Catolica San Antonio de Murcia | Spain to be completed in 2022

Postgraduate Extended Diploma in Business Management

Cambridge International Qualifications | UK to be completed in 2022

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (Electrical) Information

University of the Witwatersrand | South Africa 2019

IEB National Senior Certificate with Advanced Programme Mathematics

St John's College | South Africa 2012

INDUSTRIES

Logistics & Market Research
Education & Training
ICT (Information & Communication Technologies)
Engineering
Insurance
Banking



Gender · Male
Disability · None
Race · Indian
Languages · English

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Senior Associate Consultant currently working as a *Data Analyst* at *IQbusiness*, with a drive in the corporate environment and the desire to apply himself to his maximum potential. Having worked on various projects where his role ranged from lead engineer to a business analyst and a data analyst, Kishan's approach to work is methodical and analytical. The execution of the task is planned accordingly, to complete all objectives in the most efficient and successful manner so that the maximum value can be added. Kishan is in the process of completing his MBA specialised in Business Analytics through UCAM University.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Associate Consultant · IQbusiness | Johannesburg, South Africa

11/02/2021 - Current
Associate Consultant

29/01/2020 - 11/02/2021

Responsibilities: Kishan has worked as a business analyst on an internal project as well as an external project. He has successfully performed the role of a Data Analyst for Genex Insights and worked as an analyst within Absa's model risk space that would lead to a tactical journey in 2021. Currently, Kishan is a Data Analyst consulting to Nedbank's Ghost team.

Teaching Assistant · University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa

Responsibilities: Kishan was required to help run, execute and demonstrate laboratories and tutorials. In doing so he required extensive knowledge of C++, SFML, GitHub and Git collaboration. Throughout the course, Kishan assisted the students in a variety of ways relating to their work.

Intern · Liberty Life Head Office | Johannesburg, South Africa

07/2017

28/11/2016 - 18/01/2017

06/05/2016 - 17/06/2016

Responsibilities: Kishan worked in the IT department of the company assisting the HOD in various projects. The projects tasked to Kishan ranged from data collection, database management, network mapping, system analysis, C++ and VBA programming and Excel programming.

Intern · MICROS South Africa (Pty) Ltd | Johannesburg, South Africa # 26/06/2015 - 03/07/2015

Responsibilities: Kishan was challenged with analysing C# code for an ongoing project and was tasked with converting the project into C++. Following this, Kishan had to design and implement a basic user interface for the analysed code.

Kishan Narotam

</> TOOLKIT

Software Development

MATLAB · C++ · Java · HTML · CSS · NodeJS · Assembly · Python

Project Management

Scrum · Kanban · MS Project · Trello · Test Driven Development

Databases

MySQL · MS Access

Continuous Integration

Analysis

MS Excel · Power BI · Tableau

Technical Writing

MS Word · MS PowerPoint · MS Outlook · MS Visio · LaTeX

Graphical Editing

Adobe Premiere Pro

CERTIFICATES

IBM (Coursera)

Data Science Professional Certificate (IBM Data Science) · 16/01/2021

Data Science Foundations Specialization · 08/12/2020

Applied Data Science Capstone · 16/01/2021 Machine Learning with Python · 14/01/2021

Data Analysis with Python · 24/12/2020

Databases and SQL for Data Science · 08/12/2020

Python for Data Science and AI · 01/12/2020

Data Science Methodology · 20/11/2020

Tools for Data Science · 17/11/2020

Data Science Orientation · 10/11/2020

Microsoft

MTA: Database Fundamentals: Certificate 2020 15/09/2020

ICAgile

ICAgile Certified Professional · 04/05/2020

Tableau

Tableau Author · 29/05/2020 Tableau Consumer · 26/05/2020

IQbusiness

UX Design Bootcamp · 21/08/2020

UiPath Academy

RPA Business Analyst Foundation · 12/08/2020 RPA Starter Training · 03/03/2020



in /in/kishan-y-narotam/

/KNarotam

== PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst · Ghost Squad

Nedbank Group | Johannesburg, South Africa

01/02/2021 - Current

Project Overview: The Ghost pipeline is responsible for unsecured lending in Nedbank, namely credit card, personal loan and overdraft. Recently, a new type of unsecured lending is being implemented as part of home loans and is in development. The overall objective is to optimise and make the pipeline and environment more efficient both in being used and monitoring from a business and technical perspective.

Responsibilities: Kishan documented the weekly and monthly process that occurs in the Ghost pipeline into a wholistic document that can be utilised for both business and technical teams to ensure that the processes are described and understood. Kishan is also working on creating a dashboard to allow for data error and data loss analysis.

Analyst · Model Risk Data Discovery and Design Absa Group Limited | Johannesburg, South Africa **iii** 28/07/2020 - 11/12/2020

Project Overview: The model risk architecture and processes for credit regulatory reporting are sub-optimal in terms of business efficiencies being realised across the value chain. The project team developed a target state architecture and roadmap identifying opportunities for unlocking sustainable efficiency. Subsequently, the project team took the various stakeholders through various roadshow presentations to gain valuable buy-in on the identified opportunities and created a project charter for the initiatives.

Responsibilities: Kishan was an analyst supporting the team in a variety of manners. In the first phase of the project, Kishan defined various role profiles for stakeholders in the model risk space, mapped out necessary frameworks, policies and standards for a clearer understanding. In the subsequent phase, Kishan assisted in creating a project charter for a tactical journey that will occur in 2021, identifying benefits and associated metrics.

Data Analyst · MultiChoice Africa Genex Insights | Johannesburg, South Africa **(1)** 09/03/2020 - 31/07/2020

Business Analyst · IQbusiness Talent Management Solution IQbusiness | Johannesburg, South Africa

06/02/2020 - 25/02/2020

Business Analyst · IAM AfricaAccess | CSO Testing Proposal Absa Group Limited | Johannesburg, South Africa **#** 30/01/2020 - 04/02/2020

Lead Engineer · Design of a Thermally Controlled System for Medications University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa **#** 17/09/2019 - 25/10/2019

Co-Lead Engineer · Image Compression Based on Non-Parametric Sampling in Noisy Environments

University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa **#** 01/07/2019 - 11/09/2019

For a more comprehensive view of all certificates; testimonials; projects and subsequent responsibilities can be found on CV tab of my website or at the link below.

https://knarotam.github.io/Pages/CV/CV.html